[{"id": "5867fd59de129f031133932c", "question": "What series of movies starring Clifton Webb was adapted to a TV show in 1985?", "answer": "Mr. Belvedere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f7b6fe83fe1f2a824c25", "question": "Which Christmas carol became the first song ever to be broadcast from space?", "answer": "Astronauts Tome Stafford and Wally Schirra sang \"Jingle Bells\" from space on 16 December 1965.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f168e3f7c52aae91cc07cb", "question": "What is the core in most pencils made from?", "answer": "Graphite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b5f9fb6c85e9e634ff46", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32360ebf195a31e15d73b6", "question": "What character was invented to respond to questions from Gold Medal Flour customers?", "answer": "Betty Crocker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8e", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Van Winkle?", "answer": "Vanilla Ice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b970eee65b76b9f266a", "question": "The Ptolemy dynasty ruled which ancient kingdom?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d1", "question": "For what movie did Jack Nicholson win his first Academy Award?", "answer": "One Flew Over The Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e046fe83fe1f2a824b89", "question": "What U.S. President refused to use the telephone while in office?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15e", "question": "What year was Mother Teresa born?", "answer": "1910", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cf", "question": "What name is given to trees that lose their leaves annually?", "answer": "Deciduous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe698bb20565ad31a57c738", "question": "Who kept Odysseus trapped on a remote island for seven years.", "answer": "Calypso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f8dafa5fdd6dd25324f2", "question": "Where did we meet Newkirk, Carter, LeBeau and Kinchlow?", "answer": "Hogan's Heroes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba5", "question": "Which country is the third largest one in Africa?", "answer": "Sudan\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7336deec85e375820b220", "question": "What British general surrendered to Japanese forces at the Battle of Singapore?", "answer": "Arthur Percival", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e88d06d333868d34d74a", "question": "Where will you find these ruins of a temple for Hercules?", "answer": "Amman, Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74e", "question": "What city, located in the Sonoran desert, was once called Arizona City?", "answer": "Yuma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a862cb8751d53e7d75f9", "question": "United States' observation of Mardi Gras was started in which city and state?", "answer": "Mobile, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b1", "question": "What large island is the most western point of land in Alaska?", "answer": "Attu Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60077f91bd51d85e222ab63d", "question": "What school of art grew out of the poetry of Romanian-born Tristan Tzara?", "answer": "The\u00a0Dada\u00a0school of art, or Dadaism was born out of the widespread disillusionment created by World War I.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c602", "question": "The moons of Uranus are named after characters from the works of what writers?", "answer": "Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb04", "question": "Which member of the British royal family was married to Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1d", "question": "What Grimm's fairy-tale character is named for a vegetable craved by her pregnant mother?", "answer": "Rapunzel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad9", "question": "What Grand Slam sports event is held at Flushing Meadows, NY?", "answer": "US Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8eb", "question": "Graphite dust is formed when what is cut with a laser?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37c", "question": "Who developed the classification we use for clouds?", "answer": "Luke Howard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b598", "question": "Which band's song was the 1 billionth iTunes download?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6fb1a9e54d890926f6d2", "question": "Which country is home to the colorful Rainbow Mountain?", "answer": "Peru -- AKA Vinicunca, it achieves its vibrant hues thanks to natural weathering, which has exposed mineral strips in the earth.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f9", "question": "In the movie \"Stand By Me\", what did Gordy, Chris, Vern and Teddy set out to find?", "answer": "A Body", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc1", "question": "What is a gricer interested in?", "answer": "Trains", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab53", "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which Central European country?", "answer": "Slovenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffb241cf6db9ac4808cf5", "question": "What is the oldest city in India?", "answer": "Varanasi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc060948005ec986edcda", "question": "Who is the first member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Heejin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaba", "question": "What is the capital of Solomon Islands?", "answer": "Honiara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab82", "question": "Sierra Leone lies along the shores of which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338895", "question": "What has no reflection, no shadow and cannot stand the smell of garlic?", "answer": "A vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ab8a16490a8cc1a6e528d", "question": "In what year was the first Call of Duty game released?", "answer": "2003", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb58dd5dad637d903c8812", "question": "What is Bhutan's national sport?", "answer": "Archery -- It was born out of necessity as bows and arrows were used to repel Tibetans and British invaders in the 19th century.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4a", "question": "What was the name of the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88e", "question": "What kind of stone is Georgia's Stone Mountain?", "answer": "Granite", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4f", "question": "What year saw the release of the first \"Planet of the Apes\" movie?", "answer": "1968", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd969ce23c87fd04dd15e0d", "question": "What was Thomas Edison's nickname?", "answer": "The Wizard of Menlo Park", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3d", "question": "What disease devastated America's population of Elm trees?", "answer": "Dutch Elm Disease", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad3", "question": "An English fire hydrant is said to be the inspiration behind the unique bottle of what liquor brand?", "answer": "Tanqueray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f3", "question": "What sport was once contested with a spadroon?", "answer": "Fencing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca56", "question": "What do insects do through their spiracles?", "answer": "Breathe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb2a1ac9bff04efae6d75c", "question": "Which UK band had a No. 1 hit in 1965 with their song \"I'm Alive\"?", "answer": "The Hollies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbe", "question": "What instrument did bandleader Glenn Miller play?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ff", "question": "Lucille Fay LeSueur became famous as who?", "answer": "Joan Crawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aca001dd7bf43be5e76f", "question": "The pavlova dessert is named after a professional in what artistic field?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ec", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1984 film \u201cStarman\u201d?", "answer": "Jeff Bridges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358a485db0d66a186cb552", "question": "Which countries does Bangladesh share a land border with?", "answer": "India and Myanmar (Burma)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c2", "question": "What do the letters MG stand for in the British sports car?", "answer": "Morris Garage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccdbaec223966ae8f88ad", "question": "In \"Gone With the Wind\", what gift does Rhett bring back from New Orleans for Mammy?", "answer": "A petticoat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c730", "question": "What vitamin group, important for vision and bone growth, includes retinol?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f7", "question": "Which game series features a demon-slaying character named Dante?", "answer": "Devil May Cry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922c", "question": "What New York City night spot was the subject of a 1984 Richard Gere movie?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e7", "question": "What tree measurement do foresters usually make at 4 feet above ground level?", "answer": "Girth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b572", "question": "What is Grappa?", "answer": "An Alcoholic Drink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b341", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339663", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who has the largest collection of Malibu Stacy dolls?", "answer": "Mr. Smithers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e96d06d333868d34d755", "question": "Which is the world's oldest island?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0adf0e662d71a53650fb5", "question": "Who became famous for painting New Mexico landscapes from her Model A Ford?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbb", "question": "In Roman mythology who killed Remus?", "answer": "Romulus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c563", "question": "What name is given to a triangle with all equal sides?", "answer": "Equilateral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975c", "question": "Helen Mirren won best actress Oscar, beating out Meryl Streep, for which 2006 movie?", "answer": "The Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aeb", "question": "The Christmas carol \"Jingle Bells\" was first published in what year?", "answer": "1857", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac35", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was alive?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42e", "question": "How old was Alfred Hitchcock when he died?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a9", "question": "What is an angle whose measure is between 0 and 90 degrees referred to as?", "answer": "An acute angle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b5", "question": "To counter slipping sales, what was marketed, beginning in 1987, as \"the other white meat\"?", "answer": "Pork", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be57efc5415ba52ed6f0aa8", "question": "Viticulture is the growing and harvesting of what plants?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f0", "question": "What kind of oil, a product of the flax plant, is used to make most oil paints?", "answer": "Linseed oil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af80", "question": "Who did Dwight Eisenhower defeat twice in presidential elections during the 1950s?", "answer": "Adlai Stevenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c536", "question": "What planet is tilted on its axis more than any other?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d1", "question": "In which film did Kevin Costner make his directorial debut?", "answer": "Dances with Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339096", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hera?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c6", "question": "Singer Stefani Joanne Angelina Germanotta is better known by what stage name?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6e", "question": "What medical facility was founded in Rochester, Minnesota, in the late 1800s?", "answer": "Mayo Clinic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339974", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's real full name?", "answer": "Lenford Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e90906d333868d34d750", "question": "What country were cars invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ef", "question": "In a 2003 movie, Diane Lane plays a writer who buys a villa in what region of Italy?", "answer": "Tuscany", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774411284458f1d785442c", "question": "The International Headquarters of the United Nations is surrounded by what city?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4e", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Girl in the Kremlin\"?", "answer": "Natalie Darryl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b5b606d333868d34d6ec", "question": "Which country was the first European nation to reach Japan?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b813", "question": "What is the Jewish New Year called?", "answer": "Rosh Hashanah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b941", "question": "What 4 tournaments make up golf's Grand Slam for men?", "answer": "Masters, PGA, U.S. & British Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b48a249076251badbeaa3", "question": "What name did astronaut Jonh Glenn give to the space capsule he used to orbit the Earth in 1962.", "answer": "Friendship 7 -- Glenn was the first American to orbit the Earth when he circled the Earth three times in a Mercury space capsule.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc9", "question": "What can a lycanthrope do ?", "answer": "Change into a wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980f", "question": "What is rapper Drake's full name?", "answer": "Aubrey Drake Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df1", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"pariah\"?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68d", "question": "The leaves of the eucalyptus tree are the only food that what animal will eat?", "answer": "The koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a176", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Bridge on the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f28c73aa70ea0b70afd", "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35e", "question": "What was the first country to have a public monorail system?", "answer": "UK", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958d", "question": "What song did Wayne and Garth listen to on their way to the doughnut shop in the movie \"Wayne's World\"?", "answer": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba9f67e83c707845b20da", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88b", "question": "What is the point value of the letter Z in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e6", "question": "What does the Ring of Fire surround?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339711", "question": "Boo Boo is the companion of which cartoon character?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d3", "question": "Where in Egypt is the Tomb of Tutankhamen?", "answer": "Valley of the Kings", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b498e662d71a53650fec", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" books?", "answer": "A. A. Milne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f564a533a95c66dc4fe750", "question": "Which character did Jack Nicholson portray in the 1974 film \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J. Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7d", "question": "Who plays the coach of the German dodgeball team in the 2004 movie \"Dodgeball: A True Underdog Story\"?", "answer": "David Hasselhoff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b353", "question": "Who assassinated John Lennon?", "answer": "Mark David Chapman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcb", "question": "What movie featured the fictional band \"The Soggy Bottom Boys\"?", "answer": "O Brother, Where Art Thou?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aef", "question": "What sitcom character was constantly called \"Butthead\" by his bratty big brother Wayne?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b575", "question": "How many pounds does a US gallon of water weigh?", "answer": "8.3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65dbc1f3c0ead6880d620", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc0", "question": "Who met longtime best friend Gayle King in 1976?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d5a72b42d4a3561a9f04", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", when is Katchoo\u2019s birthday?", "answer": "November 19", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9df", "question": "Which branch of science is concerned with the study of matter and energy?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df5", "question": "What Broadway team collaborated on \"Flora the Red Menace\" before writing \"Cabaret\" and \"Chicago\"?", "answer": "John Kander and Fred Ebb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76904eec85e375820b2aa", "question": "What is the oldest public art museum in the United States?", "answer": "Wadsworth Atheneum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f3056f75aa2bc17b61b2acd", "question": "The song \"Afternoon Delight\" was the only major hit for which one-hit-wonder group?", "answer": "Starland Vocal Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f33", "question": "Whose paintings include \"At the Moulin de la Galette\" and \"At the Moulin Rouge\"?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af00", "question": "Who was the 16th president of the US?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b0", "question": "What is the 1919 Jallianwahla Bagh massacre also known as?", "answer": "The Amritsar massacre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac0", "question": "Lake Erie contains an artificial reef made from the pieces of which sports stadium demolished in 1996?", "answer": "Cleveland Municipal Stadium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339019", "question": "In what literary work would you find the Yahoos?", "answer": "Gulliver's Travels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9d", "question": "Who was banned from Saturday Night Live by viewer phone vote in 1982?", "answer": "Andy Kaufman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f89", "question": "Who is the author of the book \"The Life-changing Magic of Tidying Up\"?", "answer": "Marie Kondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2a", "question": "What American author created the characters of Rip Van Winkle and Ichabod Crane?", "answer": "Washington Irving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b888", "question": "Which continents have never hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Antarctica and Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c035", "question": "Who invented the Spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ceb", "question": "What musical famility's two oldest brothers, Virl and Tom, were born deaf?", "answer": "The Osmonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad1", "question": "What book is divided into 114 chapters called \"suras\"?", "answer": "The Qur'an", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597ddba577980686f722d177", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339639", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Captain Li?", "answer": "Mulan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b571c6767df192a942e3374", "question": "What three countries border the Togolese Republic?", "answer": "Ghana, Benin and Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339514", "question": "Who voiced Pinocchio in Disney's 1940 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dickie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb3414e368446ca7bd6849", "question": "What are the two most popular types of coffee beans?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd46ec223966ae8f8903", "question": "In the movie \"Ghostbusters\", what instrument does Dana play?", "answer": "Cello", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b094", "question": "What country's transcontinental railway was finally finished on November 7, 1885?", "answer": "Canada's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddd666ce05a3942286da3", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" Captain Hadley's brother left him inheritance money. What industry was his brother in?", "answer": "Railroad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5c8e6ce05a3942286e22", "question": "Who was Sports Illustrated\u2019s first female sportsperson of the year?", "answer": "Billie Jean King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5df", "question": "What color is known as \"vert\" on a coat of arms?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae45", "question": "Of what nationality was the explorer Ponce de Leon?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f9", "question": "What is the world's largest island?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa7", "question": "Who painted \"The 3rd of May\"?", "answer": "Francisco de Goya", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c714", "question": "What extinct bird got its name from a Portuguese word meaning \"simpleton\"?", "answer": "Dodo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abac", "question": "What is the capital of the state of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fad", "question": "What movie's title mission is completed using the Five-Point-Palm Exploding Heart Technique?", "answer": "Kill Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb08", "question": "Which planet is orbited by the moon Charon?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84a", "question": "How many colors are there on a Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897b", "question": "In what book did Rudyard Kipling introduce readers to a mongoose named Rikki Tikki Tavi?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfa", "question": "Besides aces, what was the other pair in Wild Bill Hickok's \"dead man's hand\"?", "answer": "Eights", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22fc8dc25ca9e12ef62c", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008df8cf842fa4c4ba96ae", "question": "In the world of wine, what does \"Chambre\" mean?", "answer": "Serve at room temperature", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a799", "question": "Opened in 1928, the original Gorky Park is an amusement park located in what world capital city?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7eb5eb24f84e0b9f9ffdd", "question": "What is the more common name for a Peritonsillar abscess?", "answer": "Quinsy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59029f9bcad1ec93f27df762", "question": "What continent does yerba mate originates from?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b891", "question": "The Tour de France was first staged in which decade?", "answer": "1900s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cc", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of Springfield's Italian chef?", "answer": "Luigi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befb", "question": "What New York Giants' bone-crushing tackle in 1985 ended quarterback Joe Thiemann's career?", "answer": "Lawrence Taylor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"War & Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067f54ff9c0647b50a8083", "question": "In October of 2016, just 2 months after its initial release, what product did Samsung stop manufacturing and selling?", "answer": "Galaxy Note 7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f5", "question": "Which Paul McCartney and Wings album includes \"Picasso's Last Words\"?", "answer": "Band on the Run", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac5", "question": "What year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c8", "question": "What instrument was Jelly Roll Morton best known for playing?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015faeefe83fe1f2a824c37", "question": "What is the name of the woman who single-handedly brought to ruins the strongest man ever, Samson?", "answer": "Delilah. Delilah is arguably the most ruthless woman ever. She connived with the Philistines to take Samson down.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c34c5815febcc896f9255", "question": "Which is the Earth's largest continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ae", "question": "How many sides does a rhombus have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339110", "question": "In which play by Tennessee Williams would you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e4", "question": "What hangs from the roof of a limestone cave?", "answer": "Stalactites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded270ea2747c8aff16d3d", "question": "Whose military autobiography was titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015dfd6fe83fe1f2a824b81", "question": "Who wrote the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine?", "answer": "Ada Lovelace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Smithers' first name?", "answer": "Waylon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28e", "question": "What are you if you are myopic?", "answer": "Near-sighted", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e0", "question": "What fashion designer owns Maxim's restaurant in Paris?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea5", "question": "What famous World War II general went into battle wearing two ivory-handled revolvers on his hips?", "answer": "General George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad35", "question": "Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. received his Ph.D. from which school?", "answer": "Boston University", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c6", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c91", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel is based on the biblical story of Cain & Abel?", "answer": "East of Eden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc7", "question": "Which food of the gods gives immortality?", "answer": "Ambrosia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942a", "question": "The 2007 movie \"There Will Be Blood\" is based on which novel by Upton Sinclair?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad0", "question": "What is the capital of Pitcairn Islands?", "answer": "Adamstown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a98a", "question": "What city named its airport after Leonardo da Vinci?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b28501dd7bf43be5e79f", "question": "What does your moon sign represent?", "answer": "Your subconscious and emotions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012186963c99d48cd169af2", "question": "Minnesota, it is illegal to tease what type of animal?", "answer": "Skunk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7d59a877e98cb97778a65", "question": "What movie depicts a society in which population and the consumption of resources are maintained by killing everyone who reaches the age of 30?", "answer": "Logan's Run", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa3", "question": "What do the Plastics call their \"slam book\" in the 2004 movie \"Mean Girls\"?", "answer": "The Burn Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fb", "question": "What CBS sitcom aired Monday nights at 9 pm, from 1951 to 1957?", "answer": "I Love Lucy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25eec56682715b82711cd0", "question": "What year did Spain start to colonize Venezuela?", "answer": "1522", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbd", "question": "In Greek mythology, what name was given to the race of one eyed giants, of whom Polyphemus was one?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de8", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"typhoon\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa9", "question": "On which island was Napoleon exiled in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfbe79616e6c6d4eba4f0", "question": "What animal can you smell a mile away?", "answer": "The skunk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338947", "question": "What is the name for a literary device that combines two words and their definitions into a single new word?", "answer": "Portmanteau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ec1ab24f84e0b9f9ffe3", "question": "The Atomium is a famous tourist attraction in which city?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a139", "question": "What band sang the song during the opening and closing credits in the film \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Simple Minds\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2123d31a458464a93c449", "question": "The Band-Aid supergroup was formed in 1984 to raise money for famine relief in what troubled African nation?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590678e5ff9c0647b50a804d", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c540", "question": "Alfred Nobel is credited with the invention of what?", "answer": "Dynamite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb4697e83c707845b2119", "question": "\"Chicken of the Woods\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Mushroom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339383", "question": "How long does a replicant live for in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af1", "question": "In which US state was Clark Kent brought up?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfd", "question": "What is widely considered to be man's first celestial observatory?", "answer": "Stonehenge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92a", "question": "Where is the Golf Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "St. Augustine, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0e1cefcbed638185eaa1d", "question": "French is the official language for how many nations?", "answer": "29", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa89", "question": "Where is Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f60301dd7bf43be5e82d", "question": "What annual event originated from the tradition of Candlemas?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba4fb874c93a3298b214b", "question": "What does Mount Snowdon roughly translate to from Old English?", "answer": "Snow hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339189", "question": "What organization do the FLash, Wonder Woman, Superman, Batman and the Green Lantern all belong to?", "answer": "The Justice League of America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92f", "question": "What yard line must a football team drive to, to reach the \"red zone\"?", "answer": "The 20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25ef3d6682715b82711cd5", "question": "The Mayflower is famous for being the first ship to transport what to the New World?", "answer": "English Puritans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdc38e347d002c297e4e5", "question": "In which film did Madonna play a character called \"Gloria Tatlock\"?", "answer": "Shanghai Surprise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47470f8e329de4f87789c", "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of the UK throughout the 1980s?", "answer": "Marget Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd7137e83c707845b2171", "question": "Which character in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" bets Andy would be the first to crack on his first night in the prison?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68b", "question": "Camp Lejeune Marine Corps Base is located in which US state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad61", "question": "Who was the president of Uganda immediately before and after Idi Amin's reign?", "answer": "Milton Obote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cd2f24f0f7a362efd541", "question": "What country is home to the Negev Desert?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c499", "question": "Which English philosopher believed that people in a state of nature are good?", "answer": "John Locke", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049896cf93664eb1048688", "question": "What is the first silent film to win an Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba3", "question": "Who wrote the play, \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ff", "question": "Which US state's official song is \"On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away\"?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c203", "question": "Which country were the 1900 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d3", "question": "What famous American was nicknamed \"The Lone Eagle\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00f", "question": "The Northern Mariana Islands became a US territory during what war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc03c6de0eb824d4052d8", "question": "How did the Pacific Ocean get its name?", "answer": "Portuguese explorer, Ferdinand Magellan named it \"Mar Pacifico\", which means \"peaceful sea\" in both Portuguese and Spanish.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60023f054be4723ccac22161", "question": "As of 2020, what was the name and breed of the tallest dog ever?", "answer": "A Great Dane named Zeus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601219dd63c99d48cd169afc", "question": "What is a haboob?", "answer": "A type of sand storm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab29", "question": "What ocean is the island of Madagascar located in?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919d", "question": "Who was the voice of Donkey in the \"Shrek\" movie series?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58be2d5c8faf425cf37add7d", "question": "Who won the Academy Award for Best Actor in 2017?", "answer": "Casey Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b918364247bf200fb888", "question": "What is the fear of flutes called?", "answer": "Aulophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b051", "question": "Who co-\u00adfounded Microsoft with Bill Gates?", "answer": "Paul Allen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd4", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"tsunami\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1c", "question": "How many battleships were sunk during the attack of Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6e", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Tale of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Ben-Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3cc544f0f6af5b066634", "question": "What year did Bill Haley and His Comets release the album \"Rock Around the Clock\"?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb73dbc5e259d7869087335", "question": "During the Kentucky Derby races, what fashion event is known as part southern tradition and part spectacle?", "answer": "The Hat Parade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a546", "question": "What is the capital of the US territory of Puerto Rico?", "answer": "San Juan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57e", "question": "What is the capital of County Kerry, Ireland?", "answer": "Tralee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338883", "question": "Who wrote Around the World in Eighty Days?", "answer": "Jules Verne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c7fa877e98cb977789da", "question": "In which capital city would you find the Marley Museum?", "answer": "Kingston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339843", "question": "Who directed the film \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be92", "question": "What do the initials stand for in PGP digital encryption?", "answer": "Pretty Good Privacy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98c", "question": "What musical instrument is played to wake up soldiers?", "answer": "Bugle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339326", "question": "In the movie \"Short Circuit\", what is the name of the robot?", "answer": "Johnny Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339109", "question": "What popular book did Viktor Frankl write in 1946?", "answer": "Man's Search for Meaning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ed", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?", "answer": "Fe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc09", "question": "What high civilian Indian award was Mother Teresa awarded?", "answer": "Bharat Ratna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339351", "question": "What was Ray's occupation on the TV show \"Everybody Loves Raymond\"?", "answer": "Sports writer", "category": "entertainment"}]